

Ire Aderinokun

I'm a 25 year old User Interface Deisgner and Front-End Developer based in Lagos, Nigeria

www.ireaderinokun.com | ire@ireaderinokun.com

Technical Skills

I design clean and user-friendly interfaces with **Sketch**, **Photoshop**, and plain old **Pencil and Paper**. I have designed interfaces for the **Web**, **iOS**, and **Android**.

As a Front-End Developer, I am well versed in the clientside technologies, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. My markup
is always semantic and accessible. I know all the ins and
outs of CSS, and can build almost any design. For largescale applications, I prefer to use the SASS pre-processor
to keep my CSS modular and maintainable and I also use
PostCSS for some extra features. I can build powerful
Progressive Web Applications using plain JavaScript.
When a framework is needed, my preference is Angular 2.
Having worked with Back-End developers building
applications, I am very familiar with how REST APIs work,
and can even navigate my way around any server-side
application.







Work Experience

Head of Technology, Big Cabal

September 2015 - Present

At Big Cabal, I lead the team building the technology powering their media assets; TechCabal and Zikoko. I work in **Project**Management, Design, and Front-End Development roles.



August 2014 - Present

I have worked on a number of projects, including designing interfaces and converting them to accessible markup, building **Progressive Web Applications**, and **Angular 2** applications.

Designer and Front-End Developer, Mobnia

May 2015 - September 2015

During my time at Mobnia, I worked on designing the Admin User Interface for a Podcasting Web Application, and developed it in **Angular 1**.







Education

Senior Web Developer Nanodegree, Udacity

May 2016 - October 2016

This Nanodegree, created in partnership with Google, develops the skills needed to create Accessible, Performant, Progressive Web Applications. Over the course, I worked on 5 applications, each designed to test specific skills needed by any modern Senior Web Developer.

MA Law, University of Bristol

2012 - 2014

An accelerated, fast-track, Masters level Postgraduate Degree in Law. I graduated with a Merit and within the top 20% of my class.

BSc Experimental Psychology, University of Bristol

2009 - 2012

Recognised by the British Psychological Society (BPS). I graduated with an Upper Second Class Honours.



More

I'm a Google Expert in Web Technologies

Google Experts are experienced, recognized developers of Google technologies as well as **outstanding professionals in their field**. They distinguish themselves through frequently speaking at conferences, share their passion and experience by publishing videos and tutorials, writing code samples, mentoring developers and startups and much more.

I speak at Developer Conferences Worldwide

I have given talks at Developer conferences across the globe, such as **Google's Progressive Web Apps Roadshow** in Sub-Saharan Africa, and **Fronteer's Conference** in Amsterdam.

I write Articles and build Open Source Tools

I have written **over 90 articles** on my blogs, www.bitsofco.de and www.helloangular.com. I have also built several open source tools used by hundreds of developers.